獲得通過。
議員發案，本會現在恢復二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案二讀辯論。咁審議上述條例草案嘅委員會主席莫乃光議員就委員會嘅報告向本會發言。莫乃光議員：主席，本人僅以二零一三年專業會計師。
修訂條例草案委員會下，稱條例草案委員會主席嘅身份，向立法會彙報誒法案委員會嘅工作嘅商議嘅工作。
二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案咧，誒下清呢個條例草案係由梁繼昌議員所提交嘅草案。條例草案主要目的係修訂專業會計師條例，允許單一執業會計師或者。
成立只有一或者誒誒允許呢個單一嘅會執業會計師成立只有一名股東嘅公司，並且咧將呢個公司嘅註冊為係執業法團啊，禁止並誒並非向香港會計師公會下稱會計師公會註冊為執業法團嘅法人團體喺佢。
嘅誒名稱入邊使用certified public accountant嘅稱謂誒英文縮寫CPA或者會計師嘅字樣，以及咧作出相關嘅技術性同埋草擬上嘅修訂。法案委員會咧係支持呢個條例草案嘅。
法案委員會咧曾經係查詢會計師公會就有關立法建議諮詢佢嘅會員嘅情況。咁會計師公會表示咧，該會會員喺二零零五年十二月嘅週年大會上邊已經通過建議修訂會計師啊專業會計師條例嘅決議案，容許。
佢單一執業會計師註冊成立執業法團。至於禁止誒使用若干句誤導性嘅稱謂、英文縮寫同埋字樣嘅建議咧，則於二零一一年五月獲得會計師公會理事會通過。理事會咧其後已經通知會計師公會嘅會。
會員有關嘅建議修訂，關於條例草案嘅一啲嘅文本嘅修訂咧，會計師公會亦都已經通知佢哋嘅會員。
就住條例草案嘅建議對於公眾嘅影響，會計師公會指出咧，公司條例喺二零零三年作出修訂，取消公司至少需要有兩名董事或者股東嘅規定，但係當時咧就並冇對專業會計師條例作出相應嘅修訂，而條例草案咧。
目的就係依據該項嘅公司條例嘅修訂咧，對於專業會計師條例作出相應嘅修訂。由於而家專業會計師條例第二十八D條已經容許單一執業會計師同埋一名名義股東成立嘅公司，並且將呢個公司係註冊為執。
業法團咧，誒條例草案關於允許單一執業會計師成立只有一名股東嘅公司咧，並且將呢個公司註冊成為執業法團嘅呢個建議咧，係唔會對公證公眾有造成影響嘅。
咁關於禁止誒並非向會計師公會註冊為執業法團嘅法人團體使用若干句誤導性嘅稱謂、英文縮寫同埋字樣嘅建議咧，會計師公會就表示呢項建議係有助堵塞漏洞，防止依類嘅法人團體試圖。
誤導公眾，相信佢哋係專業會計師條例所指嘅。
執業單位同埋符合資格提供審計服務，從而咧係保障公眾利益。
法案委員會關注，若果有公司並非根據專業會計師條例向會計師公會註冊為執業法團，但係現時已經喺佢嘅名稱入邊使用咗certified public accountant嘅稱謂，英文縮寫C.P.A.或者會計師嘅字樣，喺條例草案通過。
之後咧，呢啲嘅公司需唔需要更改名稱？會計師公會就指出，自從誒該會喺幾年前同公司註冊署商討之後咧，並非根據專業會計師條例向會計師公會註冊為執業法團嘅公司，除非佢哋已經係就名佢嘅名。
名稱獲得會計師公會嘅事先批准，並且向公司註冊處出示有關嘅批准，否則咧係唔可以喺佢哋向公司註冊處註冊名稱入邊使用上述嘅稱謂啊英文縮寫同埋字樣。條例草案咧，目的係喺專業會計師條例中明文禁止以。
上嘅誤導嘅手法。
就住條文嘅草擬方面咧，誒法案委員會同意就專業會計師條例嘅一啲現行嘅條文作出技術修訂。我將稍後咧係代表法案委員會就條例草案動議委員會誒審議階段嘅修正案，以作出一啲相關嘅技術。
術性嘅修訂。
咁主席，誒下邊就係我好少少嘅一啲嘅誒個人嘅意見。咁主席，我今次都誒代主席，我都好高興可以幫助阿梁繼昌議員咧係提出誒嘅呢個專業會計師條例嘅修訂咧，做一啲嘅工作。咁各行各業嘅專業人士咧，對於香港個經濟發展都係非常之重要。
要嘅，所以我淨係喺呢度講咧，就係希望有一日我可以喺呢度見證到一個係專業資訊科技人員嘅條例嘅誕生。咁呢個係我少少嘅願望，主席嘅緊之層次。
仲有冇其他議員想發言？
如果冇，我就現在請梁繼昌議員發言答辯。喺梁繼昌議員答辯後，辯論即告結束。梁繼昌議員。
Acting President, first of all, I would like to thank the honourable Charles Moch.
主席，委員會主席及所有委員會成員，對他們花費在審查該法案上的時間和努力，以及他們的支持表示感謝。
During the scrutiny, the legal adviser to the Bills Committee has proposed some minor textual amendments to the bill, which have been accepted by the Bills Committee.
The chairman of the bills committee will move those amendments later.
The proposals in the bill were initiated by the Hong Kong Institute of Certified Public Accountants, the Institute hereinafter.
The bill seeks to amend the Professional Accountants Ordinance (PAO) in two areas.
The first part of the bill seeks to amend section 28D and other relevant sections of the PAO to enable a certified public accountant practising.
To incorporate a company with only one director or shareholder.
and register the company with the institute as a corporate practice qualified to perform audits.
Currently, under Section 28D of the PAO.
accountancy firms are permitted to incorporate a company with limited liability.
and register the company with the institute to provide audit services to public as a corporate practice.
Audits will be performed by those directors or shareholders of such a corporate practice who are certified public accountants holding a practising certificate issued by the institute.
All directors and shareholders of corporate practices must be certified public accountants.
In a proportion of whom must be certified public accountants holding practising certificates.
under the pre-2003 companies ordinance situation.
至少兩董事和股東是要求，為有限公司的註冊。
As the corporate practice is a limited company, it had to meet this requirement too.
to enable sole practitioner firms to opt for incorporation, and at the same time satisfy the pre-2003 companies ordinance requirements.
The P.A.O. allows the institute's council to permit a person.
Who is not a certified public accountant or a certified public accountant practising?
to become a director and nominee shareholder of a corporate practice with two directors or shareholders, if the other director or shareholder is a certified public accountant practicing.
The company's ordinance, Mr. Acting Chairman, was amended in 2003 to enable a single director and shareholder to incorporate a company.
Accordingly, the requirement for a so-practising member corporate practice to appoint a non-certified public accountant as director or shareholder under the PAO has become obsolete and unnecessary.
Therefore, it is proposed in the bill to amend the P.A.O. to enable a corporate practice.
要被註冊為一董事及股東，誰是持牌公眾會計師實習？
In line with the company's ordinance.
for the existing so practising member corporate practices which have appointed a non-certified public accountant as director or shareholder.
since such appointment was required purely to comply with the requirements of the pre-2003 companies ordinance.
There is no need to continue with the requirement.
therefore, the bill also proposes to require all existing sole practising member corporate practices to convert.
within one year transitional period, to either sole practicing member corporate practices with only one practicing member.
或多資格成員合夥律師，with at least two thirds of the directors or shareholders being practising members.
The proposed amendments in the bill are made solely for the purpose of aligning the PAO requirement with the current company's ordinance.
Mr. Acting Chairman, the second proposal of the bill is to prohibit any body corporate, not being a corporate practice registered with the Institute.
從使用描述，certified public accountant。
The initials CPA in capital letters.
或的characters we can see in its name intended to cause, or which may reasonably cause any person to believe, it is a practice unit.
In recent years, it has come to the public's attention that there are companies being registered with the company registry, not being CPA corporate practices.
registered with the institute under the P.A.O., which used the description, certified public accountant.
The initials CPA in capital letters.
或的characters we can see in the names, and by so doing misled the public into believing that the companies are practice units under the P.A.O. qualified to provide audit services.
Under Section 42 of the P.A.O.
It is a criminal offence for a company, not being a corporate practice.
to use the descriptions certified public accountants practising, public accountant, the initial CPA practising, PA, all the characters執業會計師、註冊核數師、核數師或審計師 in its name, which are reserved names for professionals, qualified.
要執行命令，under the P.A.O.
However, as the current section 42 does not prohibit companies from using the description "certified public accountant", the initial CPA in capital letters, or the characters we can see in the names.
公司 may therefore be able to use such description with the intention of causing any person in the public to believe that they are practice units.
therefore the bill proposes to amend the relevant part of section 42 by adding a subparagraph prohibiting any company which is not a corporate practice from using certified public accountant (CPA in capital letters) or UGC in its name if the intention is to cause
或，which may reasonably cause。
any person to believe that it is a practice unit under the P A O.
Mr. Acting Chairman。
The proposed amendments will help plug the loophole where a company which is not a corporate practice attempts to mislead the public into believing that it is a practice unit under the PAO and qualified to provide auditing services, and hence will protect the interests of the public.
我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案予以議讀，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得經由功能團體選舉產生及分區直選選舉產生兩部分。
在席議員分別以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案。
全體委員會審議階段，本會現在成為全體委員會。我現在向各位提出嘅代議議題係以下條文納入二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案：第一、二、五、六及七條。
有冇議員、委員要發言？
我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係第一、二、五、六及七條納入本條例草案，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得由經由功能團體選舉產生及分區直選選舉產生兩部分在席議員分別以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
第三及四條。
莫乃光議員已作出預告，同意修正第三及四條。莫乃光議員。
代主席本人僅以2013年專業會計師修訂條例草案委員會主席身份，動議修正條文嘅第三、四條，誒修正案嘅內容咧，已經長在於發畀各位委員嘅文件入邊。
法案委員就參考咗法案委員會法律顧問嘅意見，同意咧由本人提出三項技術性嘅修訂。法案委員會察悉，由於條例草案第三括弧四條。
第三括弧五條，同埋第四括弧一條。
以就現時專業會計師條例第二十八D括弧二括弧C條及第四十二括弧一括弧H A條嘅一啲用詞咧，係作出修訂，為咗使條文咧個文本係一致，法案委員會同意應對現。
時嘅條文第二十八括弧D括弧三括弧C括弧ii括弧A條。
第四十二括弧一括弧ii條同埋第四十二括弧四括弧a條咧，係作出相應嘅修訂。主席，我懇請各位委員支持有關嘅修正案。
各位委員現在可以就第三及第四條原本嘅條文及莫乃光員嘅修正案進行合併辯論，有冇議員想發言？
梁繼昌議員。
代主席，嗯，呢誒幾個嘅修訂啦，都係得到會計師公會嘅同意，亦都咧係收到啊財經事務及副務局十月誒二零一三年十月十八號咧都冇反對呢啲修訂，希望個委員支持。
莫乃光議員，你是否想再次發言？
我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係。
莫乃光議員動議嘅議修正案予以通過，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得經由功能團體選舉產生及分區直選直接選舉產生兩部分在席委員分別以過半數贊成，我宣佈修正案獲得通過。
經修正的第三及四條，我現在向各位提出嘅代決議題係經修正嘅第三及四條納入本條例草案，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得經由功能團體選舉產生及分區直接選舉產生兩部分在席議員分別以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
全體委員會現在回覆為立法會三讀《二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案》。
梁繼昌議員。
代主席，二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案經修正後已通過全體委員會審議階段。我動議此條例草案予以三讀並通過。我現在向各位提出嘅代議議題係二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案。
予以三讀並通過。
有冇議員要發言？
我現在向各位提出上述代決議題。
現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題。
獲得經由功能團體選舉產生及分區直接選舉產生兩部分在席議員分別以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。二零一三年專業會計師修訂條例草案。
議員議案。